PAULO B. ALZAGA

480.330.2194 | Paulo.Alzaga@hotmail.com

Professional Summary

From travel professional to full-stack developer. Interested in challenges that produce results and provide satisfaction. Extensive sales and customer service experience, branching out to develop new skills in front and back end coding. I enjoy identifying and creating solutions for problems. Currently enrolled in a six-month full stack developer boot camp, graduating October 2018. Excellent organizational, communication and problem-solving skills.

Skill Highlights

- JavaScript, jQuery, Node.js, Github, HTML, CSS
- Bilingual in Spanish and English
- Started and ran own business for 2+ years
- Dependable, honest detail and goal oriented
- Extensive customer service and sales training
- Microsoft Office, Outlook, Salesforce, Concur, Amadeus, Sabre
- Over 20+ years of travel and tourism experience
- Lived and worked abroad on multiple occasions
- Volunteer for City of Hope and helping take care of friend on occasion who has leukemia

Experience

STA Travel

Jan 2004 – Mar 2018

Senior Travel Expert - Chandler, AZ

- Created highly complex itineraries for a variety of clientele world-wide, paying close attention to detail while ensuring client satisfaction and exceeding company goals
- Explored various international destinations to gain further knowledge of culture, tourism trends and vendor products.
- Crossed trained by working in various departments throughout tenure
- 2006 Travel Expert of the Year
- 2004, 2005, 2006 Presidential retreat for highest revenue achiever
- Invited to work at STA Australia division after having travel around the world for over a year

Centex Home Equity

04/2003 - 12/2003

Loan Officer - Tempe, AZ

- Assisted clients with refinancing their sub-prime mortgages
- Reviewing key documents and assessing information to identify potential loan opportunities

Account Executive 08/2001 – 04/2003

Hilton Hotels – Dallas, TX

• Receiving the "Excellence in Sales" award and nominated for the Circle of Excellence; one of Hilton's most prestige sales awards

- Working closely with Lockheed Martin and the newly created Transportation Security Agency (TSA) accounts, generating over three million in revenue
- Generated almost four million in revenue for 2002
- Inducted into the Hilton Millionaire Dollar Club for having generated over a million dollars in revenue in a single month
- Recognized by management as Employee of the month twice for outstanding teamwork and performance
- Extensive networking within the Hilton family as well as prospective clients
- Maintaining and developing various account types, working closely with multiple departments to help capture increased market share and representing over 2500 Hilton branded properties, both domestically and internationally

Food and Beverage Manager

05/1999 - 03/2001

Radisson Woodlands Plaza – Flagstaff, AZ

- Worked over 50 hours per week while taking attending university full-time
- Responsible for approximately 15 employees, assisting in a variety of duties including: scheduling, employee/guest complaints, employee development, tracking inventory and budgeting
- Acted as Manager on Duty for 182 room property when required
- Simultaneously oversaw two restaurants, lounge and catering department

Education

Full Stack Developer

Apr 2018 – Present

The University of Arizona – Gilbert, AZ

Bachelor of Science, Hotel and Restaurant Management

Sep 1997 – May 2001

Northern Arizona University – Flagstaff, AZ

Study Abroad – International Hospitality, Tourism and Events Management

Jan 1999 - Jul 1999

Leeds Metropolitan University – Leeds, England

Study Abroad – International Tourism

Summer 2001

Netherlands Institute of Tourism Studies – Breda, Netherlands